A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H FA317
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Publicity
  - Publicity - Time and Life Magazines, 1928-1961 (Box 148, Folder 1134)
    1928 article on John D. Rockefeller; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s objections, 1944, to description of John D. Rockefeller as "robber baron." Article on Princeton class of 1932, including Laurance S. Rockefeller. Various proposed articles; interest in article on organized charity; John D. Rockefeller 3rd interest in articles on Asia - his criticisms. David Rockefeller declined to join Board of Time, Inc. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, T. J. Ross, Allan Nevins, Henry R. Luce.
    19.1T
  - Publicity - Time and Life Magazines, 1958 (Box 148, Folder 1134A)
  - Publicity - Time and Life Magazines - Sports Illustrated, 1954-1961 (Box 148, Folder 1135)
    Declinations of various proposals, invitations.
  - Publicity - Time Magazine - Article on John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1956-1959 (Box 148, Folder 1136)
    Cover story on John D. Rockefeller, Jr. as philanthropist; letters to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and to Time regarding the Article; requests for autographs. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Publicity - Wichita Kansas Beacon, 1935-1955 (Box 148, Folder 1137)
    Tear sheets of articles on family, friendly and defensive; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on some of the articles. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., L. Levand.
    19.1W
  - Publicity - Requests for Articles and Statements, 1921-1939; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 148, Folder 1138)
    Requests to various Rockefellers; some statements and interviews - none particularly important. Copy of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1927 Princetonian address, "Business of Being a Father;" draft of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1955 unpublished article on Protestant unity. Attempts to get Laurance S. Rockefeller investment in magazines. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Horace Wade, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, T. J. Ross.
    19.2
  - Publicity - Requests for Articles and Statements, 1939-1944; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 149, Folder 1139)
  - Publicity - Requests for Articles and Statements, 1945-1961; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 149, Folder 1140)
  - Publicity - Requests for Articles and Statements, 1959-1961 (Box 149, Folder 1140A)
  - Publicity - Requests for Articles and Statements - Horace Wade, 1923-1925 (Box 149, Folder 1141)
    Boy reporter interviewed John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Publicity - Requests for Articles and Statements - Interview at Ormond, 1935-1937 (Box 149, Folder 1142)
    Off the record interview with representatives of United Press International (UPI), Associated Press (AP), and International News Service (INS); discussed John D. Rockefeller's health; account published in 1937.
  - Publicity - Scripps-McRea League of Newspapers, 1937-1939 (Box 149, Folder 1143)
    19.21
  - Publicity - Scripps-McRea League of Newspapers - Home Made Stewards, 1922 (Box 149, Folder 1144)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interview on upbringing of children reprinted and retitled.
  - Publicity - Scripps-McRea League of Newspapers - Newspaper Enterprise Association, 1920-1929 (Box 150, Folder 1145)
    Requests for statements declined.
  - Publicity - Denver Post, Kansas City Post - H. H. Tammere, 1915-1923 (Box 150, Folder 1146)
    Negro newsman became friendly with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on Colorado trip; kept John D. Rockefeller, Jr. informed of his activities. 1918 article on John D. Rockefeller's human-ness.
    19.3
  - Publicity - Denver Post, Kansas City Post - F. D. Bonfils, 1915-1933 (Box 150, Folder 1147)
    Friendly to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. after Colorado trip.
  - Publicity - New York American, 1925-1936; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 150, Folder 1148)
    Favorable articles on John D. Rockefeller; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. discussion, 1912, with Brisbane and Dana S. Creel regarding cure of venereal disease. Advertising policy of Standard Oil, 1913; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined Brisbane's offer of interest in paper; 1918 attacks on family by Hearst based on National Security League Association. Regarding size of family fortune. 1922, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. statement on successful men. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Arthur Brisbane, J. D. Greene, George Creel.
    19.4
  - Publicity - New York American, 1911-1936; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 150, Folder 1149)
  - Publicity - New York American, 1911-1936; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 150, Folder 1149A)
  - Publicity - New York American - Libel Suit, 1908 (Box 150, Folder 1150)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. decision to sue American for story of "peonage" at Corn Products Company, Chicago.
  - Publicity - New York American - Christmas Fund, 1923-1935 (Box 150, Folder 1151)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to New York American Christmas Fund.
  - Publicity - New York Journal American - Hearst Papers, 1927-1960 (Box 150, Folder 1152)
    Declination of various proposals and invitations; Journal American's citation of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for outstanding contributions to New York City. Correspondents include W. R. Hearst, Jr., Ivy Lee.
  - Publicity - New York Journal American - Hearst Papers, 1940 (Box 150, Folder 1152A)
  - Publicity - New York Journal American - Hearst Papers - Gerald Frank Article, 1938 (Box 150, Folder 1153)
    On Rockefeller brothers.
  - Publicity - New York World, 1911-1930 (Box 150, Folder 1154)
    Requests for interviews; comments on paper and its editorial; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. arranged meeting with Ralph Pulitzer and Ivy Lee to discuss World's attacks on Rockefellers in Colorado. Special John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interview arranged. Correspondents include Ivy Lee, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ralph Pulitzer, Fred Lawrence.
    19.5
  - Publicity - New York Press Club, 1909-1934 (Box 151, Folder 1155)
    Appeals for contributions declined usually; $100 given in 1928. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard.
    19.6
  - Publicity - Tarrytown Daily News, 1911-1938; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 151, Folder 1156)
    Relations with paper and its editors; comments on editorials and stories. Disagreements with editors; publication of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letter. 1959, Nelson A. Rockefeller named Man of the Year. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, W. Odell, W. J. Cannon.
    19.7
  - Publicity - Tarrytown Daily News, 1939-1960; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 151, Folder 1157)
  - Publicity - Tarrytown Daily News, 1953-1960; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 151, Folder 1157A)
  - Publicity - Tarrytown Daily News - February Letter Regarding Activities in Community, 1935-1939 (Box 151, Folder 1158)
    Letter regarding family activities prepared by office, printed in paper's anniversary issue.
  - Publicity - Tarrytown Daily News - Clippings, 1930-1960 (Box 151, Folder 1158A)
  - Publicity - New York Globe, 1908-1924 (Box 151, Folder 1159)
    1908 purported interview with John D. Rockefeller; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on paper's editorials. Globe article favorable to John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Industrial representation, oil industry. Refusal to invest in Globe. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ivy Lee, Bruno Blinen.
    19.8
  - Publicity - New York Globe - Summer Camp Fund, 1916-1918 (Box 151, Folder 1160)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $100 per year for three years.
  - Publicity - New York Times, 1912-1961; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 151, Folder 1161)
    Thanks for friendly articles; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.-A. S. Ochs correspondence. Declinations of requests and invitations; correction of inaccuracies. Laurance S. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd appearances on New York Times Youth Forum. Regarding S. J. Woolf's sketch of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Adolph Ochs, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. J. H. Finley, Louis Wiley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, A. H. Sulzberger, Rachel McDowell.
    19.9
  - Publicity - New York Times, 1954 (Box 151, Folder 1161A)
  - Publicity - New York Times, 1912-1949; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 151, Folder 1162)
  - Publicity - New York Times - P. W. Wilson Interview, 1937 (Box 152, Folder 1162A)
    With John D. Rockefeller, Jr. regarding church unity.
  - Publicity - New York Times - Neediest Cases, 1920-1961 (Box 152, Folder 1163)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and children's contributions to charity organization society - sent through the New York Times "100 Neediest" fund.
  - Publicity - New York Times - Neediest Cases, 1961 (Box 152, Folder 1163A)
  - Publicity - New York Times - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Letter, 1940-1941 (Box 152, Folder 1164)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. spoke out regarding convoying of supplies to allies, suppression of Nazi and communist activities in U.S. Letter prepared by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, sent to Sulzberger. Prompted by Lend Lease Bill. Suggestions for newsreel and radio appearances declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
    19.91B
  - Publicity - New York Times - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Letter - Clippings, 1941 (Box 152, Folder 1165)
    Clippings; newspaper reprints and comments.
  - Publicity - New York Times - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Letter - Letters of Approval, 1941; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 152, Folder 1166)
  - Publicity - New York Times - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Letter - Letters of Approval, 1941; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 152, Folder 1167)
  - Publicity - New York Times - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Letter - Letters of Disapproval, 1941 (Box 152, Folder 1168)
  - Publicity - Chicago Evening Post - J. C. Shaffer, 1915-1922 (Box 152, Folder 1169)
    Friendly Colorado editor moved to Chicago; compliments to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on his industrial plan, urged wide distribution of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.' ideas. Correspondents include J. C. Shaffer, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19.10
- Taxes
  - Taxes - Taxation - General, 1932-1958 (Box 152, Folder 1170)
    Interest in tax laws; plans and organizations for lowering taxes. Realty taxes. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Clark Mecum.
    37
  - Taxes - Ohio, 1905-1921 (Box 153, Folder 1171)
    John D. Rockefeller's Cleveland taxes, taxes on Coventry-Mayfield Land Company, Ohio bonds; taes on various properties. Tax problem regarding John D. Rockefeller's New York residency. Lists of appraisals. John D. Rockefeller's tax case in Supreme Court. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy, Bertram Cutler.
  - Taxes - Tarrytown, 1937-1938; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 153, Folder 1172)
    Payment of tax lawyers for Mt. Pleasant and North Tarrytown properties. Court case regarding Mt. Pleasant assessments. William Rockefeller's letter to John D. Rockefeller regarding Hudson property assessments. Nothing from 1901-1921. Hiring of local tax lawyer. List of taxes. The Archville case. Material regarding Tarrytown consolidation. Correspondents include William Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    37A
  - Taxes - Tarrytown, 1937-1938; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 153, Folder 1173)
  - Taxes - Tarrytown, 1896-1947; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 153, Folder 1174)
  - Taxes - Tarrytown, 1939-1960; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 153, Folder 1175)
  - Taxes - Tarrytown - J. J. Sinnott, 1916-1929 (Box 154, Folder 1176)
    Payments to Tarrytown tax attorney.
  - Taxes - Tarrytown - Lists (Box 154, Folder 1177)
    Lists of state, county and town taxes paid by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in Greenburgh, Tarrytown and Mr. Pleasant.
  - Taxes - Tarrytown - 1939 Letter to Board, 1939-1940 (Box 154, Folder 1178)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. offer to waive tax refunds after 6-year litigation resulted in decision in his favor. Reaction of town officials; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letters to persons in family regarding matter.
    37B
  - Taxes - Tarrytown - 1939 Letter to Board - Copies of Letter (Box 154, Folder 1179)
    Three copies of September 12, 1939 letter.
  - Taxes - Tax Statements - New York City, 1930-1938 (Box 154, Folder 1180)
    Lists of assessments on 4 West 54th Street.
    37.1
  - Taxes - New York City Taxes - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1931-1940 (Box 154, Folder 1181)
    Real estate taxes on various properties.
  - Taxes - New York City Taxes - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - New York Personal Tax, 1905-1932 (Box 154, Folder 1182)
    Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s personal property taxes.
  - Taxes - John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1906-1929 (Box 154, Folder 1183)
    Miscellaneous correspondence regarding assessments for personal estate, United States income tax, taxes on dividends, etc. Correspondents include E. V. Cary, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Taxes - John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Assessments - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1901-1919 (Box 154, Folder 1184)
    Personal property tax.
  - Taxes - John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Special Tax - Brokers License, 1916-1928 (Box 155, Folder 1185)
  - Taxes - Tax Policy League, 1936-1957 (Box 155, Folder 1186)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller anonymous contribution to League supplying tax information; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution for acquisition of headquarters. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Beardsley Ruml, Phillip Keebler.
    37.2
  - Taxes - American Taxpayers Association, 1934-1953 (Box 155, Folder 1187)
    Group sought to lower taxes on the rich, repeal 16th amendment; requested contributions. Ignored.
    37.3
  - Taxes - American Taxpayers Association - Western Tax Council, 1939-1957 (Box 155, Folder 1188)
    J. A. Arnold's attempt to get 16th Amendment repealed. E. Parmalee Prentice's interest. Crackpot material from Bluford Balter. No family interest.
  - Taxes - Tax Foundation - Citizens Public Expenditure Survey, 1937-1949; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 155, Folder 1189)
    Organization sought economy in government; Nelson A. Rockefeller one of original sponsors. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. annual contributions until 1946. Invitations to dinners; reports on activities and finances. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    37.4
  - Taxes - Tax Foundation - Citizens Public Expenditure Survey, 1937-1949; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 155, Folder 1190)
  - Taxes - Tax Foundation - Citizens Public Expenditure Survey, 1949-1958; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 155, Folder 1191)
  - Taxes - Tax Foundation - Citizens Public Expenditure Survey - Contributions, 1941-1949 (Box 155, Folder 1192)
    Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Rockefeller Center, Inc.
  - Taxes - Citizens Emergency Committee on Non-Defense Expenditures, 1941-1943 (Box 155, Folder 1193)
    Non-partisan, non-profit, non-political committee sought to keep public informed on government fiscal affairs; involvement with Tax foundation. No Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    37.5
  - Taxes - Citizens Public Expenditure Survey, 1939-1959 (Box 155, Folder 1194)
    New York state group, in cooperation with Tax Foundation, made surveys of city governments and published results. Mainly printed material; no requests. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    37.5A
  - Taxes - Income Tax - General, 1915-1933; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 156, Folder 1195)
    Adjustment of taxes; committees on tax reform; tax exempt status of charitable organizations. Court opinions regarding taxes; refusals to participate in moves for new legislation. Memos regarding various aspects of income tax regulations. Correspondents include George Wallace, F. R. Blair, David Rockefeller, Robert Bates, Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Winthrop Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, W. R. Gregg.
    38
  - Taxes - Income Tax - General, 1933-1961; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 156, Folder 1196)
  - Taxes - Income Tax - 1917 Dividend Case, Douglas vs. Edwards, 1924-1927 (Box 156, Folder 1197)
    Observation of case.
  - Taxes - Income Tax - 1917 Dividend Section 1106(a) Revenue Act, 1927-1928 (Box 156, Folder 1198)
    Refunds denied.
  - Taxes - Income Tax - Town vs. Eisner, Stock Dividend Case, 1918-1920 (Box 156, Folder 1199)
    Constitutionality question; lawyers' fees.
  - Taxes - Income Tax - 1927 Refund, 1927-1928 (Box 156, Folder 1200)
    Increase in refund on 1917 taxes.
  - Taxes - Income Tax - 1933 Tax Case (Box 156, Folder 1201)
  - Taxes - Income Tax - Tax Refunds, 1949-1953 (Box 156, Folder 1202)
  - Taxes - Income Tax - Tax Refunds, 1959 (Box 156, Folder 1202A)
  - Taxes - Income Tax - Philip F. Keebler, 1933-1937 (Box 156, Folder 1203)
  - Taxes - Inheritance Taxes, 1921-1950 (Box 157, Folder 1204)
    Advice regarding reduction of taxes. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    38.1
  - Taxes - New York State Tax, 1914-1934 (Box 157, Folder 1205)
    Regarding New York City Tax Reduction Committee, New York tax laws, Otto Kahn's "Two Years of Faulty Taxation," (including copy marked by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.) and League for Sound Taxation. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, E. V. Cary, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    38.2
  - Taxes - New York Tax Reform Association, 1900-1934 (Box 157, Folder 1206)
    Aims to change tax laws; John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interest and contributions.
    38.3
  - Taxes - New York Tax Reform Association - Contributions, 1913-1923 (Box 157, Folder 1207)
    John D. Rockefeller annual contributions.
  - Taxes - New York Tax Reform Association - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1918-1923 (Box 157, Folder 1208)
  - Taxes - Federal and State Unemployment Tax, 1935 (Box 157, Folder 1209)
    Regarding John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s liability for tax for their employees. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, George C. Williams.
    38.4
  - Taxes - Tarrytown - 1939 Letter to Board - "Certiorarias vs. Village of North Tarrytown", 1934-1939 (Box 186, Folder 1433)
    Bound volume of documents and clippings.
- Requests for Photos of Art Objects
  - Requests for Photos of Art Objects, 1958-1961 (Box 157, Folder 1210)
    Martha Baird Rockefeller policy against allowing photographs of her art objects to be used publicly. Policy for other members of family in their files. Correspondents include Martha Baird Rockefeller.
    84
- Washington, D.C. Appeals
  - Washington, D.C. Appeals, 1944-1961 (Box 157, Folder 1211)
    Small gifts to Washington organizations; ambitious programs for Washington activities declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    105
  - Washington, D.C. Appeals, 1956-1961 (Box 157, Folder 1211A)
  - Washington, D.C. Appeals - Temple of Understanding, 1960-1961 (Box 157, Folder 1212)
  - Washington, D.C. Appeals - Temple of Understanding, 1961 (Box 157, Folder 1212A)
  - Washington, D.C. Appeals - Washington Community War Fund, 1942-1955 (Box 157, Folder 1213)
    Contributions.
- Form Letters
  - Form Letters, 1912-1936 (Box 157, Folder 1214)
    Samples of letters used to decline routine requests; some printed. Also samples of legal documents used by office, other papers.
    163
- Foreign Mail
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Argentina, Austrian Jews, African Students, 1930-1960 (Box 157, Folder 1215)
    191A
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Argentina, Austrian Jews, African Students, 1946-1960 (Box 157, Folder 1215A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Argentina, 1946-1960 (Box 158, Folder 1216)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Brazil, 1952-1960 (Box 158, Folder 1217)
    191B
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Brazil, 1958-1959 (Box 158, Folder 1217A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Belgium, 1930-1960 (Box 158, Folder 1218)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Belgium, 1954 (Box 158, Folder 1218A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Canada, Canal Zone, Chile, Columbia, Cuba and Czechoslovakia, 1930-1961 (Box 158, Folder 1219)
    191C
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Canada, Canal Zone, Chile, Columbia, Cuba and Czechoslovakia, 1939-1961 (Box 158, Folder 1219A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Canada, 1946-1961 (Box 158, Folder 1220)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Canada, 1956-1961 (Box 158, Folder 1220A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Czechoslovakia, 1930-1938 (Box 158, Folder 1221)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from China, 1929-1960 (Box 158, Folder 1222)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from China, 1943-1960 (Box 158, Folder 1222A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from China - Chinese Intellectual Refugee Act, 1951-1953 (Box 158, Folder 1223)
    No action.
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from China - Chinese Intellectual Refugee Act, 1952-1953 (Box 158, Folder 1223A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from China - Madame Chaing Kai-Shek, 1943 (Box 158, Folder 1224)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. spoke at Madison Square rally.
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from China - Chinese Students Christian Association, 1941-1948 (Box 158, Folder 1225)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd gave $300.
  - Foreign Mail - China Famine Relief, 1928-1937 (Box 158, Folder 1226)
    Appeals declined.
  - Foreign Mail - China War Relief, 1937-1961 (Box 159, Folder 1227)
    Problems of aiding Chinese without provoking Japanese retaliation against Peking Union Medical College (PUMC). Some small gifts by John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Foreign Mail - China War Relief, 1941, 1960-1961 (Box 159, Folder 1227A)
  - Foreign Mail - China War Relief - Church Committee for China Relief, 1941-1948 (Box 159, Folder 1228)
    Gifts by John D. Rockefeller 3rd and David Rockefeller.
  - Foreign Mail - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1939-1957 (Box 159, Folder 1229)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributions, 1938-1940.
    191C1
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1940-1951; Folder 1 of 6 (Box 159, Folder 1230)
    Development of program; family contributions; John D. Rockefeller 3rd an active participant on board.
    191C2
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1941-1950; Folder 2 of 6 (Box 159, Folder 1231)
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1946-1947; Folder 2 of 6 (Box 159, Folder 1231A)
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated - M. M. Jones Survey, 1941 (Box 159, Folder 1232)
  - Foreign Mail - China Relief Legion (Box 159, Folder 1233)
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1941; Folder 3 of 6 (Box 160, Folder 1234)
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1941-1942; Folder 4 of 6 (Box 160, Folder 1235)
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1941-1942; Folder 4 of 6 (Box 160, Folder 1235A)
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1942-1944; Folder 5 of 6 (Box 160, Folder 1236)
  - Foreign Mail - United China Relief, Incorporated, 1945; Folder 6 of 6 (Box 160, Folder 1237)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Denmark and Dominican Republic, 1938-1957 (Box 160, Folder 1238)
    191D
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Denmark and Dominican Republic, 1957 (Box 160, Folder 1238A)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Equador, Egypt, Ethiopia, 1937-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1239)
    191E
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Ethiopia - H. Selassie, 1954-1957 (Box 160, Folder 1240)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from Ethiopia, 1935-1948 (Box 160, Folder 1241)
  - Foreign Mail - Appeals from England, 1940-1947; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 160, Folder 1242)
    191E1